# Diego Kourchenko

601 Country Club Rd Eugene, OR LinkedIn

## Summary

The past 4 years I have been involved in various leadership projects around the community, including leading the design and development of software applications for commercial use and providing tech mentoring at tech events. My professional career includes 3 years managing diverse teams and developing production-ready software applications. My education at Oregon State University focuses on artificial intelligence and distributed networks.

#### **EDUCATION**

## Lane Community College

Eugene, OR

Email: dkourchenko@gmail.com

Mobile: (678) 908-0605

github.com/Kourchenko

Associate of Science: Computer Science

## Oregon State University (OSU)

Corvallis, OR

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science GPA: 3.56

# Expected Graduation: 2021

#### EXPERIENCE

# SpeedUpAmerica (Open-Source Project)

Eugene, OR

Lead Frontend Developer (NodeJS, Ruby/Rails, Typescript)

April 2019 - Present

- Website Development: Developing and maintaining website to map broadband coverage, provide transparency about internet speed coverage across America, and inform community leaders for areas without internet coverage.
- Community Involvement: Providing technical knowledge support and guidance for meetings with community leaders, community constituents, and business development constituents.

#### 4J Eugene School District Program

El Camino Elementary Eugene, OR

Coder In Residence

April 2019 - May 2019

- Technical Support (Robotics): Provide networking support for 20-30 WiFi-connected robots, linked to interactive website to control individual robots.
- Teaching (Spanish/English): Provide bilingual lessons on importance of technology, information about how computers are networked together, the interface between hardware software, and how to apply CS skills.

## **CBT Nuggets**

Eugene, OR

Developer Intern (NodeJS, React, AWS Tools)

June 2018 - March 2019

- Website Development: Development and maintenance of API and interactive website to track and create new seating-chart reservations across 3 building locations using Drag-n-Drop interactive map.
- Cloud Systems: Development of continuous integration API to automate software development and code deployment to provide support for software development team for developing new applications.

### Acme Cone

Eugene, OR

Machine Production Manager

January 2015 - June 2018

- Management: Lead cutting department team of bilingual employees to operate CNC Machinery.
- **Technical Support**: Reduced cutting-time procedures by 45% and minimized material waste from 35% to 10%.
- Data Collection: Responsible for weekly, monthly, and quarterly material inventory Excel Spreadsheet. Responsible for producing CNC Machinery daily-production executive reports.
- **Software Development**: Proposed plan and lead development of two test mobile applications for automated estimates.

## PROJECTS AND COMMUNITY INVOLVEMENT

- Hack for a Cause: Committee Advisor for yearly hackathon to bring community ideas to fruition.
- Coder In Residence: Bilingual Robotics program success featured in Register Guard.